Manuel!
It's okay. We had to tie her down.
I need a mirror. Now! At least 3 feet high.
Move! Go, now!
No!
Show yourself.
Smile pretty, you vain prick.
For your boss.
Pull it!
Most cops go 20 years without firing their guns.
Why do I always know where these guys are?
Where to aim, when to fire.
I'm wondering, is there something wrong with me, Father?
Something damned?
God has a plan for you. He has a plan for us all.
You mustn't let your faith be overshadowed by guilt.
Yeah, I'm trying.
I'm trying real hard.
Isabel.
And now I'm gonna be done in by this.
Wouldn't be the first, John.
Come on, Les.
You saved me before, you can do it again, right?
This is aggressive.
Twenty years ago, you didn't wanna be here.
Now you don't wanna leave. Yeah, that's a good idea.
John, you really need to prepare.
- She fell from the roof? - She jumped.
No.
I know it's hard to accept. She was sick.
- Isabel wouldn't kill herself. - Angie.
She wouldn't kill herself. Period!
Angie, there were security cameras.
A new case?
The big score? The mother Iode? The one you've been waiting for?
- Humor me. - Don't I always?
I just pulled a soldier demon out of a little girl.
Looked like it was trying to come through.
Yeah, I know how it sounds.
We're finger puppets to them, John, not doorways.
They can work us, but they can't come through onto our plane.
Check the scrolls anyway. See if there's any precedent.
- That's not the way this works. - Haven't I served him enough?
- What does he want from me? - Only the usual.
Self-sacrifice, belief.
- I believe, for Christ's sake. - No, you know.
And there's a difference. You've seen.
I never asked to see. I was born with this curse.
A gift, John. One that you've squandered on selfish endeavors.
I'm pulling demons out of little girls. Who's that for?
Everything you've ever done, you've only ever done for yourself.
To earn your way back into his good graces.
Impossible rules, endless regulations...
Who goes up, who goes down and why.
Hey, buddy, got a light?
Should've minded your own business, exorcist.
Not some angry half-breed. A full-fledged demon, on our plane.
Clearly I do not have to remind you that is impossible.
And yesterday I saw a soldier demon
trying to chew its way out through a little girl.
John, demons stay in hell, angels in heaven,
the great détente of the original superpowers.
Thanks for the history lesson, Midnite. You've been a tremendous help.
I need to use the chair.
John, forgetting the fact that it would almost certainly kill you,
you know I am neutral.
And as long as the balance is maintained, I take no sides.
My sister was murdered yesterday.
- Sorry to hear. - Thanks.
She was a patient at Ravenscar. She jumped off the roof.
Thought you said she was murdered.
Isabel wouldn't have taken her own life.
Yeah. What kind of mental patient kills herself? That's just crazy.
Just before my sister was committed, she became deeply paranoid.
She started talking about demons, angels.
Now, I think someone got to her, Mr. Constantine.
I think they brainwashed her into stepping off that roof.
Some kind of legion or cult.
Sounds like a theory, detective. Good luck.
- What? - We should go. Now.
What is that?
Wings.
Maybe talons.
You're kidding. Of what?
Something that's not supposed to be here.
That's really not going to help.
- Close your eyes. - Why?
Suit yourself.
Demons stay in hell, huh?
Tell them that.
Don't worry. Happens to everyone the first time.
It's the sulfur.
Sulfur.
Was it supposed to be hot or cold?
In front of the chair.
I can't believe I'm doing this.
- These are all Isabel's things? - Yeah.
- How about the cat? - Duck? Yeah, why?
Duck.
- You think that's strange. - Cats are good.
Half in, half out anyway.
Angela.
Jesus!
- Constantine, what...? - Twins.
What?
- You were twins. - What did you say?
- She killed herself. - What?
And she's damned for it.
How is this possible?
I need to eat.
you find a way out.
- You tried to kill yourself. - I didn't try anything.
Officially, I was dead for two minutes.
But when you cross over,
time stops.
Take it from me, two minutes in hell is a lifetime.
When I came back,
I knew all the things I could see were real.
Heaven and hell are right here. Behind every wall, every window.
The world behind the world, and we're smack in the middle.
Angels and demons can't cross over onto our plane.
So instead we get what I call half-breeds.
I call it hypocritical bullshit.
So when a half-breed breaks the rules,
I deport their sorry ass straight back to hell.
I don't get them all,
but I've been hoping to get enough to ensure my...
- Retirement. - I don't understand.
I'm a suicide, Angela.
When I die, the rules say I've got just one place to go.
Maybe she left something else. Not something a cop would find.
Something just for you.
You were her twin, Angela. Twins tend to think alike.
- I'm not like my sister. - But you were once.
When you were kids. When you'd spend every second with each other.
You'd start a sentence, she'd finish it. You'd get hurt, she'd cry.
- That was a long time ago. - That kind of bond doesn't disappear.
There is nothing here.
When we were girls,
we would leave each other messages.
In light.
In breath.
On the windows.
"The sins of the father would only be exceeded by the sins of the son."
- Whose son? - But he can't cross over, B.
- Impossible to cross over. - Whose son? God's son?
No, the other one. Devil had a son too.
Here it is.
This is the sign of Mammon, the son of the devil.
Hold on, it says here...
No, wait, wait, wait. I'm reading. Seems to be a loophole.
Always a catch.
It says first Mammon would have to possess a very, very powerful psychic.
- Isabel. - But that wouldn 't be enough.
To cross over, Mammon would need divine assistance.
To cross over, Mammon would need the help of God.
- Beeman? - John, look...
I know you've never had much faith, you've never had much reason to...
But that doesn't mean that we don't have faith
in you.
Beeman?
Drive. Fast.
Beeman!
Sulfur.
By the time we were 10, they started forcing her to take antipsychotics
and have treatments.
They would come for her and she'd look at me, and she'd say to me, "Tell them."
"Why don't you tell them, Angie, that you can see them too?"
But I lied.
I said:
"I don't see anything."
Until one day,
I finally stopped seeing.
I abandoned her, John.
I left her all alone.
I need to see what she saw.
You do this, there's no turning back.
You see them,
they see you.
Understand?
Yeah.
Normally, only a portion of the body has to be suspended,
but you wanted the crash course.
Yeah, I wanted the crash course.
- So, what's gonna happen? - Lie down.
- What do you mean lie down? - You have to be fully submerged.
- For how long? - As long as it takes.
Take a deep one.
God.
God, all those people.
Isabel!
I've always known. I've always known where they are.
I've always known where to find them,
where to aim and where to duck
and I've always known where they were.
I've always known that it wasn't luck.
I've always known that I could see.
It was his.
Rolling.
Not a ball.
Something smaller.
Shiny.
Balthazar.
Fire? I was born of this.
How's Mammon crossing over, you half-breed piece of shit?
That's better. Au naturel.
"Stay in the car, wait here."
Men.
Not really, no.
You can't cheat it this time. You're going back to hell.
True, but you're not.
- What are you doing? - I'm reading you your last rites.
Spare me your remedial incantations.
You do know what it is to truly be forgiven?
To be welcomed into the Kingdom of God.
Demon in heaven.
I'd love to be a fly on that wall.
You're not a priest. You have no power.
Just tell me how Mammon is crossing over
and you can go back to your shithole.
Okay, Bally, enjoy it.
The blood of God.
He found it.
Whatever killed the son of God
will give birth to the son of the devil.
My work here is done.
What are you laughing at?
She was my only mission,
and you brought her right to us.
Jesus didn't die nailed to a cross. He was killed by a soldier's spear.
The Spear of Destiny.
I'm a Catholic, John. I know the Crucifixion story.
I drew out the sister as you asked.
She's been made flush and ready.
Beeman said Mammon needed divine assistance to cross over.
How's the blood of God's only son?
The stains on the spear.
- Yeah. - So he gets the spear.
He still has to locate a powerful psychic.
Not really.
Twins.
Where's the amulet?
- Wait here. - Yeah.
- The balance. - Screw the balance.
You dare? In my house?
Is this neutral? Bullshit.
You're the only one still playing by the rules, Midnite.
And while you've been imitating Switzerland, people are dying.
Hennessy, Beeman, they were your friends once too, remember?
I need your help!
Consider it a last request.
Midnite!
- Any luck? - That's a word for it.
Holy shit. You're Papa Midnite, aren't you?
There's no use sitting on the bench if you're not ready to play, right?
You wouldn't have one of those enchanted crosses here in a cabinet.
John, no offense. I just don't think that it's a great idea
you going on a solo mission to save the world. That's my vote.
I don't know what pops thinks, but that's...
Take him, John. Kill him after.
- What are you doing? - Praying.
Praying. Okay.
Come on.
Half-breeds, right?
A birth like this, they're definitely gonna be guarding her, right?
Yeah.
We can get through them. I mean, that cross has gotta work, right?
It's not always like it is in the books.
Hi.
My name's John.
You are in violation of the balance.
Leave immediately or I will deport you.
All of you.
Go to hell.
Holy water?
Angela.
John?
John!
Shit!
Angela, what is it?
Get it out!